Welcome to all of you
我們歡迎各位今天來到我們中間
I have a very short message to you
我有一個很短很短的訊息
不過這個訊息是非常之重要的
This is a very important message
Even though it is a short message
But a very very important message
And this verse in the Bible says
Give thanks in all circumstances
For this is the will of God in Christ Jesus for you
這裡說到
凡是謝恩
因為這是上帝在基督裡面
向你們鎖定的心意
這個就是上帝要我們所做的
Now you have to pay attention
The Bible does not tell us
That we have to give thanks for everything
Including evils
Including injustice
Including sufferings in our lives
The Bible is not telling us to do this
聖經不是在告訴我們
為到所有的事來感謝
包括一些邪惡的事
或者受難的事
或者一些很不好的事發生在我們身上
一些邪惡的事
The Bible is not telling us to give thanks for everything
聖經不是叫我們為所有的事來感謝
聖經叫我們做什麼呢
在凡事上可以去感謝
凡事上
每一個的情況處境裡面
可以去感恩
The Bible is telling us
Give thanks in all circumstances
Including unhappy circumstances
Including some of the painful moments that we have
We can give thanks
And we have the resource to give thanks
In all of the circumstances
That's what the Bible is talking about
聖經告訴我們
我們有這樣的資源
我們有這樣的能力
可以在每樣的處境裡面
去感謝神
去感激上帝
Now we thank God
We can thank God
To be with us, to be present with us
In hard times
In difficult times
我們在困難的時候
我們可以去感謝上帝
仍然跟我們同在
And we can thank God
That nothing, including unhappy moments
All of this happened outside
Nothing outside of His wisdom for us
如果有一些不好的事發生在我身上
我們可以感激上帝
因為所有的事
都在上帝的恥意
上帝的智慧的裡面
發生在我們的生命裡面
我不知道你有沒有玩過一個遊戲
一個遊戲是
一個叫《I Spy》的遊戲
給你一幅圖
裡面是很複雜的
你就可以找一些東西
I don't know if you have played this game
called《I Spy》
And I give you an amazingly detailed picture
And you have to find what I want you to find
Have you ever played that《I Spy》?
Something like this
In a very complicated picture
You have to find the happy smiling onion
All right? Can you see that?
On the right?
You can find it, right?
Why don't we do this game right now?
我們一起玩一下這個遊戲,好嗎?
就在這個幅圖裡面
去找這個happy onion
這個在笑的很開心的洋蔥
笑洋蔥,好嗎?
找到了嗎?找到舉手,好嗎?
當然找到了,雞腩這麼大隻
Of course you can find it right now
But I'm going to show you the first picture
And you have to find me the happy smiling onion
All right?行不行?
在這個很複雜的圖畫裡面
下一幅給你
你就要找這個smiling happy onion, ok?
Why don't we do it by table, ok?
我們用桌子來做一個組別,好嗎?
看看你的桌子能不能找到
讓大家在桌子上找到開心的洋蔥,好嗎?
第一個就是這個,好嗎?
所以我們來找到開心的洋蔥,好嗎?
開心的洋蔥
如果找到了,舉手,好嗎?
現在我必須告訴你們,這裡有三個
這裡有三個開心的洋蔥,好嗎?
它在哪裡?它在哪裡?
好,它在右邊嗎?
它在右邊嗎?
右邊還是左邊?
好,那裡有一個大的洋蔥
然後右邊的洋蔥在左邊
你能找到第三個洋蔥嗎?
這張桌子能找到第三個洋蔥嗎?
它在哪裡?
左下方,是的,是的
你能找到它嗎?
是的
這些就是開心的洋蔥,好嗎?
你能找到第三個洋蔥嗎?
好的,你必須注意,好嗎?
你們能找到多少洋蔥?
有哪些洋蔥找不到?
找不到,不要緊,我給你第二次機會,好嗎?
我給你第二次機會,好嗎?
第二次,準備好了嗎?
好嗎?我們一邊找桌子,好嗎?
這是第二次
好的,我肯定你們能找到第一次洋蔥
是的,那是第三次洋蔥?
那是第三次開心的洋蔥?
第三個洋蔥在哪裡?
在桌子上
它在哪裡?
找桌子,你能找到它嗎?
好的
為什麼它要這麼久?
是的,我找到了
你找到了,它在哪裡?
在桌子旁邊
哦,在桌子旁邊
好的,我們開始吧
好的,你能找到多少洋蔥?
有哪些洋蔥找不到?
那個開心的洋蔥
是的,找到了,你不是老花
好的,我給你最後一次機會,好嗎?
我們試試看,好嗎?
準備好了嗎?
我給你第三張圖片
這裡
洋蔥在哪裡?
當然你可以找到第一次洋蔥和第二次洋蔥
第三個洋蔥在哪裡?
你們又找到了嗎?
哦,因為它距離電視台更近
它在哪裡?
瓦諾,它在哪裡?
它就在那裡
好的
這裡有洋蔥
開心的洋蔥
這就是我們要做的事情
我們要給予感謝
我們要給予感謝的運動
我們要找到要給予感謝的東西
這就像在複雜的圖片中找到快樂的洋蔥
這個遊戲有點像我們一整年來感恩節的時候
我們找找有什麼值得我們感恩的
有什麼值得我們去感激上帝的
我們需要很仔細地去想一想
這就跟上帝說的一樣
聖經不是說一些正面的思想就夠了
聖經是在告訴你
有一個理解上帝在給予感謝的背後
因為我們感激的時候
我們就想起這位上帝是怎樣的
我們認識這位上帝是怎樣的
上帝在控制一切
上帝有所有的東西都在祂管理的底下
這年給你發生了什麼事?
我肯定就像這張圖片一樣
非常複雜
所以我想要你為我做一件事
就是尋找一些方法
讓你感激上帝的這年
我們這年已經過了11個月
今年已經過了11個月
試著想一想今年有什麼值得去感恩的
你必須想一想
你必須回想
回想今年發生了什麼事
試著回想今年到現在
有什麼值得去感激上帝
尋找一些東西你可能會錯過
尋找一些東西可能你錯過了
你看不見的
有些東西你應該要感激的
這就是 Bible 說的
是你的生命的培養
培養你的靈魂
讓你能在控制上帝
和帶領著你的上帝
一直以來
這是一個培養我們心靈培養心靈的雜作
我們去尋找有什麼值得我們去感激
嘗試在這些細節裡面去尋找
上帝有什麼值得我們去感激
有一個著名的亞洲寫作者
叫做 Alex Haley
有一個很出名的黑人作家
在二十世紀
叫做 Alex Haley
在 Alex Haley 的辦公室裡
他是一個很有名的作家
在他的辦公室裡
有一幅畫
叫做 Turtle on Fencepost
Turtle on Fencepost
在一個這麼出名的作家的辦公室裡
他有一幅這樣的畫
聽說這幅畫就是木柱上的龜
木柱上的龜
為什麼他在辦公室裡放了這幅畫
他說每當我感到自豪的時候
我會看著龜在木柱上
我記得龜在這幅畫上沒有倒下
他有幫助
每次他說他很自豪的時候
他的事業很好的時候
他找到很多的時候
很多成功的時候
他就說
看看這隻龜
這隻龜在木柱上
不是他自己上去的
這隻龜是怎麼能夠爬上去的
是有其他人幫他上去的
I think this is the perfect analogy
for our life
我們的生命就好像是這樣
Of course this phrase post turtle
is often used politically
talk about dumb politician
當然這句話
木柱上的龜常常在政治論壇上說
說一些很蠢的政治家
怎麼能夠爬上去
But this is an analogy for our life
We didn't get there by ourselves
We had help
and ultimately God has helped you
God has brought you to this place
to this spot
這句話告訴我們生命裡面是什麼
我們不能夠自己去到這個地方
不能夠來到今天
因為我們需要其他人幫助我們
也接受了其他人幫助我們
最重要的就是上帝已經幫助我們
上帝施恩給我
所以我今天來到這個地方
So in the season of Thanksgiving
We can call this
Give thanks because of
Because every time you look at this picture
As Alex Haley said
We don't get there by ourselves
We had help
and ultimately God has helped us
That's why we thank God
這就是這個作者所說
見到一隻龜的時候
你就會知道你就是那隻龜
你就是龜
你能夠上到去
來到這裡
來到現在這個地方
是因為上帝
他終於上帝幫你
Now we can call this Thanksgiving exercise
Give thanks because of
You have success
and you have come to this place
Because of the well-being God has granted you
Because of shelter and security
That should not be taken for granted
Because of the opportunities
That is right in front of you
So that you can grow
And that is granted by God
And the small joys in your life
That should not be taken to be granted
And ultimately Jesus Christ and his cross
The love of God
The grace of God
To be with you
That should not be taken granted for
什麼叫做感恩
因為就是想起今年
上帝給我們生命
上帝給我們健康
給我們庇護我們的安全
不同的機會
事業的機會
人際之間的機會
工作的機會等等
生活裡面一些小快樂的地方
這些全部都不是理所當然的
And最重要的
是基督耶穌的十字架
上帝自己的愛
一直陪伴
和我們一起
This is what we call
Give thanks because of
Right
So try to rewind this year
What had happened to you
What have you gone through
Think about the grace of God
Think about the providence of God
想一想上帝對你的庇護
對你的帶領
這些不是理所當然的事
這些是值得去感恩的
因為如此如此
And then there is another level
of giving thanks
Not only giving thanks because of
It's giving thanks even though
Giving thanks even though
去感謝上帝縱使
即使發生這些事
Even though there were challenges
and setbacks in your life
There are small inconveniences
frustrations that happened this year
unanswered prayers
perhaps many of those
imperfections in your life
imperfection struggles
flaws that make you more real
make people more real
make your family
and your relationships more real
more authentic
So think about some difficulties
you have faced this year
to help you grow in resilience
to help you grow in patience
想一想你生命裡面今時今日
來到這裡
今年有什麼值得感恩
即使有些挑戰
有些挫折
有些不便
有些令我們很沮喪的事
或者未得到回應的祈禱
或者有些不完美的事
這些事都是上帝給我們的
上帝帶我們經過
以致我們在這些挫折
或者一些不便的當中
我們去學習
使我們生命進前一步
有不完美的事
生命裡面的不完美
和我們的家人有很多不完美
有很多關係上面不完美
令我們更加真實
這些就是叫感恩
即使
感恩 即使
最重要的是我們要記得
我們必須記住
耶穌基督和祂的墳墓
儘管這些事都發生了
要記得上帝對我們的恩典
十字架上的恩典
即使這件事發生
即使那件事發生
聖誕節的生命
現在我們要結束我們今天的祈禱
我想邀請你去做一些事
我想你去想一想
有什麼值得感激上帝的
我們想做一些事
作為教會和家人
作為靈性的家人
我們想一起做一些事
好像一個家庭一樣
在你的桌子上
你會找到一些鞋帶
一些破損的鞋帶
一些鞋帶碎片
這些鞋帶是為了贈禮
OK,wrapping up a gift
這些鞋帶你在桌子上找到的
我們想一起去做一件事
去感激我們的上帝
這些鞋帶、這些彩帶
是我們去包禮物的時候用的
Now I want you to do something together
Let's do something together
Let's rewind what had happened this year
就想想我們今年發生了什麼事
有什麼值得感謝上帝
What is worthy of giving thanks
Either setback or challenges or opportunities
or something that is good
some blessings in your life
Count the blessing
Count the things that we should be thankful for
and I want to invite you to use the permanent marker
to write it on the ribbon
This is your gift of giving thanks
Let's take a moment
to think about what we can give thanks for this year
and think about it
It takes time
Look into the details
看看心靈裡面
今年的圖畫可能是很複雜
但仔細一點去看看
仔細一點去想一想
有些什麼我是漏了
我應該是感謝上帝的
and I want to invite you to do so right now
It can be very general
in the well-being, health, success
small successes in your life
可能心靈裡面有一些很平常的看似
有家庭
有心靈
有健康
上帝的保守
I want you to write it on the ribbon
I want you to do one thing today
If God has remind you
at least one thing you should be thankful for
maybe one thing you have missed to give thanks for
I want you to write it on the ribbon
and then you bring it up here
You can leave your seat
and after you have written the items of thanksgiving
on the ribbon
you can hang it on the cross in front of me
好嗎
我歡迎你寫了之後
你向上帝做一個祈禱
or do a small prayer
You say, "God, thank you"
You write it down and bring your ribbon
and hang it on to the cross in front of me
在十字架上面
你可以帶上來
將你那個絲帶掛上去
一個十字架上面